Guide to the Debra Danburg Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Debra Danburg Papers
1977-2003
2004-001
Danburg, Debra
12.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The collection consists mainly of media records such as articles, magazines, news clippings and newsletters. The collection also contains bills, bill analyses and proposals, speeches and brochures. Other printed materials in the collection include invitations to events, directories, certificates, cards and campaign originals. The ephemeral material consists of pins, posters, special license plates and framed photographs.
Biographical Information:
Debra Danburg was a representative of the Democratic Party in the state of Texas from 1981 to 2003. She was a dynamic leader who brought about significant changes in many outdated laws. She is an attorney in private practice and has dealt with many criminal, as well as civil, cases. Debra Danburg represented district 137 in Houston, which encompassed Montrose, The Heights, Memorial Park, Greenway Plaza, Highland Village, the Galleria and Gulfton areas in Houston.
Debra Danburg was born in Houston in the year 1951. The Danburgs are long-time residents of the Heights, part of the District which Danburg served. She began working on her bachelor’s degree at the age of 16 at the University of Houston. She actively took part in the Student Association and was eventually elected for the post of vice-president in 1973-74. Danburg obtained a bachelor’s in sociology in 1974 and in 1979 received her law degree from the University of Houston Bates College of Law. She served as an administrative aide to Ron Waters from 1976-1980 before she ran for election as a Democratic Party candidate for the former District 79.
During the five years that she worked for Waters, Danburg researched, wrote and encouraged legislation. She was involved in issues ranging from the Equal Rights Amendment to street and sewer repairs. She obtained governmental appointments for constituents and prevented the merger of two local precincts, which would have disenfranchised voters. She was also a member of the Democratic Executive Committee during this time.
Debra Danburg was elected to the 67th Legislature for her first term in 1981. She served on various committees during her tenure in the Legislature. She was the Chair of the Elections Committee during the 73rd and 74th Legislatures (1993-1997) and of the Subcommittee on Budget & Oversight in the 71st Legislature (1989-1991). Danburg was also the vice-chair of the Committee on Cultural and Historic Resources. Additionally, she was a member of the Committees on State Affairs, Business and Industry, Criminal Jurisprudence, State Affairs and Appropriations.
Debra Danburg was instrumental in bringing about legislation concerning women’s reproductive rights. She strongly opposed pro-life groups and successfully upheld laws protecting a woman’s right to choose. Danburg also argued for an “open mind” on abortion in order that women could have “clean, licensed and safe” abortions, thus preventing unnecessary deaths resulting from illegal and unsafe clinics.
One of her most significant achievements as a legislator was the passage of HB 1730, which made important changes in the old rape laws. Danburg coined the term “sexual assault” to replace “rape” which would henceforth include all genders and all acts of rape and attempted rape. The bill signified the amount of violence involved in the acts and hence removed any kind of “pleasure” references. Her law became a model for other states and was eventually applied nationwide. Danburg was also successful in passing HB 263, which ended spousal exemption from sexual assault. Spouses could now report marital rape, which eventually could lead to prosecution. She also introduced a landmark bill on stalking to join those other states where stalking was considered an offense.
Another of Danburg’s important accomplishments was the passage of the “3-G” legislation. She was the first woman to pass this bill, which would stop parole and “good time” early release of criminals convicted of capital murder, aggravated kidnapping, aggravated robbery or aggravated sexual assault. It was observed that these criminals often commit violent acts within one year of their release. With the passage of this bill, such criminals would not be released until they served their full terms. Danburg also supported alternative punishments based on the brutality of the crimes. Some of the options included drug rehabilitation counseling, restitution centers and boot camps. She sponsored legislation that endorsed the Sexual Offender Treatment Program, aimed at rehabilitating sex crime offenders before they got out of prison. She supported the idea of reserving prisons for the worst offenders.
Danburg sponsored a number of initiatives toward preventing hate crimes. She worked to pass legislation which would grant and protect the rights of gays and lesbians. Her proposals sought to restrain perpetrators of hate crimes against homosexuals, religious groups and racial minorities. She filed legislation preventing discrimination based on race, color, sex, religion, origin, or sexual orientation. She was responsible for introducing the first bill to allow marriages with no regard to sexual orientation. HIV/AIDS also was another major concern for Danburg. She passed legislation to facilitate easy purchase of drugs like AZT, to protect the right to insurance regardless of blood tests, and to create councils to aid state and local agencies to fight HIV and AIDS. She supported organizations such as the Houston Gay & Lesbian Political Caucus, AIDS Foundation of Houston and The Diana Foundation, and she actively took part in Lesbian/Gay Pride Week.
The last of Debra Danburg’s major concerns, represented in this collection, was the Electric Utility Restructuring bill. Danburg was part of a delegation that visited California and Pennsylvania in order to study their utility models and hence implement a similar model in Texas. The bill allowed customers to choose their electric provider and, conversely, the providers could compete with each other to give their customers the best deals.
Danburg also was involved in many other issues concerning METRO and the Southwest Freeway in Houston, as well as a number of other concerns local to Houston. As a member of the House for twenty-two years, she was an experienced leader who played a key role in ensuring equal opportunity and justice to Texas citizens.
Danburg was the recipient of many awards within and outside the legislature. She received the Best Legislator Award during her first year at the Capitol. She received the Most Effective Legislator Award by the National Organization for Women and, in recognition of her activities, received the Outstanding Legislator Award in 1990 by the Texas Association of Symphony Orchestras. Her list of other awards include Alumna of the Year from the UH College of Social Sciences (1993), the Women’s Suffrage Award (1991) and the Environmental Defense Award (1987).
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston -- Alumni and alumnae
Genre/Form of Material:
Articles; Clippings (information artifacts); Ephemera; Newsletters; Periodicals; Photographs
Personal Name:
Danburg, Debra
Topical Term:
Legislators -- United States; Politicians; Women legislators -- Texas -- Houston; Women politicians
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists mainly of media records such as articles, magazines, news clippings and newsletters. The collection also contains bills, bill analyses and proposals, speeches and brochures. Other printed materials in the collection include invitations to events, directories, certificates, cards and campaign originals. The ephemeral material consists of pins, posters, special license plates and framed photographs.
The collection has been arranged into ten series: Media, Events, Legislature, Speeches, Electric Utility Restructuring, Campaign, Resources, Photographs, Miscellaneous and Ephemera. The above series have been arranged chronologically, while a couple is sorted topically. The materials in the collection date between 1977 and 2003 and follow original order closely.
Detailed List of Contents
- Media
  - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Education, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Heard, Goggan, Blaire & Williams, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Metro Rail, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Domestic violence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ethics, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - House committees, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - LBJ law, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Metro rail, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - AIDS, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Home Equity, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Parole, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Peace Officers, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Stalking, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Agricultural Taxes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - AIDS, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Alcoholic beverages, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Attorney’s fees, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Awards, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Caller ID, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Civic associations, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Collective bargaining, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Cultural arts, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Condoms, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Contributions, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Discrimination, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Elections, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Election committee, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Election code, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Gambling, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Gun control, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - HIV testing, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Home equity, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Housing, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Judicial campaign fairness act, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Metro, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Organics, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - No pass, no play, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pet vendor bill, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Peace officers, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photo-ops, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Rapid transit system, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Redistricting, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Revised house rules, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Retractions, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Same-sex marriage, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sexually oriented business, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Sewage, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sodomy laws, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Sexism, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Stamps & Licenses, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Southwest freeway renovations, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Stalking, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Taxation, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Telecommunications, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Term limits, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Unemployment compensation, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Utilities de-regulation, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Voter registration, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Voter registration (same day), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Women in politics, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Zoning, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Abortion, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - AIDS, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Benefits, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Breast feeding, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Civic associations, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Committees, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Election code, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Election coverage, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Endorsements, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Gambling, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - HIV testing, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - HISD, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Home equity, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Inner-city preservation, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Insurance, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Legislation, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Legislative committee, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Public access, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Sex crimes, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Sodomy laws, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - SWC, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - State bar of Texas, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - TABC, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Telecommunications, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Texas women’s political caucus, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Voter’s fraud, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Voter’s guide, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Women’s political issues, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Zoning, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Abortion, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Area codes, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Awards & honors, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Benefits, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Breast feeding, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Choice, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Criminal code, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Crisis team, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Campaign financing, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Child custody, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - DeLay, Tom, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Discrimination, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - District open house, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Domestic violence, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Donations, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Early voting, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Endorsements, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Environmental issues, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Ethics, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Fundraisers, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Gambling, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Gun control, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Harvey Milk, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Hate crimes, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Health care clinics, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Heights issues, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Highway fees, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - HIV name reporting, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Home equity, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Human rights campaign, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Hunting regulations, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Judicial campaign fairness, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Legislative committees, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Log cabin republicans, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Metro, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Montrose softball league, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Nineteenth amendment, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - North Montrose civic assn., 1995 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Parole board, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Peace officers, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Photo-Ops, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Sex crimes, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Southwest freeway, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Stalking, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Term limits, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Texas voter’s guide, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Upper Kirby district, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Utility de-regulation, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Victim’s rights, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Voter registration, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Westheimer street festival, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Women in politics, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - AIDS, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Area codes, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Awards, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Civic associations, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Congressional district, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Contributions, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Dental society LAC, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Election code, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Endorsements, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Environmental issues, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Fundraisers, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Gay pride, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Gambling, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Gun control, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Home equity, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Interviews, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Legislative elections, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Miscellaneous, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Penal systems, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Photo-Ops, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Sexually oriented business, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Southwest freeway, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Stalking, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - TORT reform, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Upper Kirby assn., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Utilities de-regulation, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Victim’s rights, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Voter’s guide, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Women’s issues, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Abortion, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Adoption, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Awards, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Election code, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Endorsements, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Energy, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - Ethics, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - Fundraisers, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Gambling, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - Gun control, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - Harris county treasurer, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - Hate crimes, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 151)
  - Home equity, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - Homestead exemptions, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Interviews, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Legislative committees, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minimum wage, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Open meetings act, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Peace officers, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Phone slamming, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Photo-ops, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Radical right, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Sex crimes, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Sexually oriented business, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Southwest freeway, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Speaking dates, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Stadium bill, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Stalking, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Tax reform, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Thank you’s, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Tobacco industry, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Upper Kirby district, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Utilities de-regulation, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Voter registration, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - White Oak bayou bridges, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Women’s health, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Abortion, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Awards, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Campaign finance report, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Contested elections, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Children’s health, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Contributions, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Cultural arts, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - CACHH, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Democratic women, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Domestic violence, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Driver’s education, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Election, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Election reform, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Electric de-regulation, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Endorsements, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Fundraisers, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Hate crimes, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Highway project, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Historic preservation, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - HIV name reporting, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Legislative study, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Memberships, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Obituaries, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Parking, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Phone slamming, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Pereira, Andres, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Stalking, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Women in politics, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - 76th legislature, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Abortion, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Adoption, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Annexation, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Arts, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Awards, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Campaign finance report, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Civic associations, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Contributions, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - DWI, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Elections, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Electric de-regulation, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Electronic campaign report filing, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Emissions, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Gun control, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Hate crimes, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Heights issues, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - HISD, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Home equity, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Houston area delegation, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Harris county, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Houston voice, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Legislative conferences, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Membership, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Miscellaneous, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Open meetings, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Pereira, Andres, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Southwest freeway, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Taxes, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Telemarketing, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Utilities, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Veggie libel law, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Vouchers, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Women in politics, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Awards, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Civic associations, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Contributions, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 92-93)
  - Elections, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Electric de-regulation, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Endorsements, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Gun control, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hate crimes, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Health issues, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Heights issues, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Interview pics, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 9-11)
  - Open meetings, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Southwest freeway, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Telemarketing, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Women’s issues, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 77th legislature, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Awards, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Campaign finance reform, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Civic associations, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Death penalty, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Domestic violence, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Driver’s license, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Eight liners, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Elections, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Electric de-regulation, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Electric restructuring, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Emissions, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, January-March 2001 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, May-October 2001 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Gender identification, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Gun control, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Hate crimes, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Heights issues, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - HISD, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 35-36)
  - Sodomy law, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Southwest freeway, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Telemarketing, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Voting age, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Wine legislation, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Abortion, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Awards, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Civic associations, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Elections, January-September 2002 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Elections, October 2002 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Elections, October-November 2002 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Environment, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Electric restructuring, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Fuel cell, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Gay/Lesbian issues, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Heights issues, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Miscellaneous, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Redistricting, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Voter fraud, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Women’s issues, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - OutSmart magazine, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - PRIDE ’01 magazine, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)